Jason Short

CONTACT INFORMATION

07817667047

Jasonshort1990@gmail.com 1 Highland Drive, Hemel Hempstead, HP3 8PT

PROFILE

I am an aspiring front end web developer searching for my first role in the software development industry. I have created my own portfolio page and hosted it using GitHub which can be viewed here – <u>Jason Short</u>. I built the site on Visual Studio Code using HTML5, CSS3, BEM and SASS. I have also built small projects using JavaScript and I am currently learning jQuery.

I am working my way through the 'Responsive Web Design' and 'Javascript Algorithms and Data Structures' certifications on Free Code Camp, have been watching Pluralsight videos, following Codecademy courses and I'm learning about SEO and accessibility.

I've worked as a Technical Author for the last two years in a software company, so I'm well versed in 'agile' methodologies and the sprint process. I've also had exposure to HTML and CSS through the launch of a new knowledge base, which I helped design, style and implement.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

2017 - Present: Technical Author, Selenity

- Implemented a new knowledge base and associated product standards using HTML and CSS.
- Contributed to cross-functional team procedures including planning, backlog refinement, storyboarding and product testing.
- Worked within various agile development teams across different cloud-based technologies, adopting scrum methodologies.
- Produced help content across multiple platforms: web, iOS, Android and Windows.
- Maintained 400+ help articles including instructional guides, feature overviews, FAQs, release notes and process diagrams.
- Proactively collaborated with stakeholders to deliver exemplary assistive support.
- Analysed customer feedback, search trends and page traffic to optimise content.
- Authored, proofed and delivered internal training plans and onboarding documentation.
- Provided contextual help including introductory text, tooltips and validation messages.

2014 - 2016: Senior Accountant, Enterprise Rent-A-Car

- Provided critical high-level reporting and analysis to a range of different departments.
- Instructed teams on new technical processes and software, delivering cross-departmental coaching to explain complex accounting issues in understandable formats.
- Maintenance and ownership of various key accounts impacting the ledger including bad debt, fixed asset management and tax calculations.
- Credit control, accounts receivable management, recovery and invoicing.
- Business management and support for rental branches, implementing strategy to maximise performance and make efficiency gains through process optimisation.

- Communicated effectively with retail and B2B clients, dealing with ad-hoc queries to provide solutions in a timely and professional manner.
- Promoted from junior accountant to senior within three months due to demonstration of leadership qualities, proactive approach and initiative in finding process efficiencies.

2013: Gap Year - Travel

Having travelled to seven different countries, connecting with people and places of many different cultures, I saw huge personal growth in confidence, communication and humility.

2010 - 2011: Accounts Assistant, Insignia Bathroom Solutions (University Placement Year)

- Sales invoicing, monthly reports, credit control, petty cash management.
- Customer service, support and aftercare, supplier issues and logistics.
- Creating and implementing a new organisational system.
- Order management, packaging and dispatch of products.

EDUCATION

2008 - 2012: BA Honours Degree - Business and Accounting (2:1), Sheffield Hallam University

2006 - 2008: A Levels - Mathematics (B), Business Studies (B), Economics (C), De Aston School

2001 - 2006: 10 GCSEs (A*- C), De Aston School

SKILLS/ACHIEVEMENTS

- Personal portfolio website Jason Short
- Basic knowledge of HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Adobe Creative Cloud experience including Fireworks, Illustrator and Photoshop.
- Imaging tool usage including Visio, Balsamiq, Camtasia and AirServer.
- Use of communication products including TFS, Trello, Slack, Hangouts and Teams.
- GCSE maths tutor 100% student pass rate.
- Mensa tested IQ of 145.
- FA Level 1 Coaching Badge Coached various junior football age groups.
- Certificate in Professional Numeracy and Literacy.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.